<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="authors">
  <heading>Authors</heading>

  <content>
         
    <p class="author-profile">
      <a href="http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/dweiss"><img
      src="img/dawid-weiss.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px"
      class="author-photo" /> Dawid Weiss</a>, the founder of the
      Carrot<sup>2</sup> project, is a researcher at the Laboratory of
      Intelligent Decision Support Systems, Institute of Computing Science,
      Poznan University of Technology, Poland.  
    </p>

    <p class="author-profile">
      His research interest include
      search results clustering, information retrieval, web mining, text
      processing, data structures and algorithms, data compression,
      linguistics, NLP. He will shortly receive his PhD degree from Poznan University of
      Technology, Poznań.
    </p>

    <p class="author-profile">
      His responsibilities in the Carrot<sup>2</sup> project include: project management,
      design and implementation of system core and components,
      Carrot<sup>2</sup> community support.
    </p>

    <p style="clear: both; margin-top: 4ex" class="author-profile">
      <a href="http://www.man.poznan.pl/~stachoo"><img src="img/stanislaw-osinski.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px" class="author-photo" /> 
      Stanislaw Osinski</a> is a
      research programmer at the Network Services Department of Poznan
      Supercomputing and Networking Center, Poland.  
    </p>

    <p class="author-profile">
      His research interests
      include search results clustering, information retrieval, text mining,
      user interface design and usability. He received his MSc degrees from
      Poznan University of Technology and The University of Sheffield.
    </p>

    <p class="author-profile">
      His responsibilities in the Carrot<sup>2</sup> project include: design
      and implementation of the Lingo clustering algorithm and other
      components, Carrot<sup>2</sup> web application User Interface design,
      project website.
    </p>

    <p style="margin-top: 4ex">
      Other contributors: 
      
      Karol Gołembniak, Irmina Masłowska (Poznan University of Technology
      (PUT), Poland, HAOG clustering component, active since 2006), 
      
      Michał Wróblewski (PUT, Poland, AHC clustering components, not active),

      Paweł Kowalik (PUT, Poland, Inductive search engine wrapper, not active),

      Steven Schockaert (University of Gent, Belgium, Fuzzy Ants clustering component, not active),

      Lang Ngo Chi (Warsaw University, Poland, Fuzzy Rough set clustering component, not active),

      <a href="http://www.dcs.shef.ac.uk/cgi-bin/makeperson?J.Nioche">Julien
      Nioche</a> (The University of Sheffield, UK, OpenSearch input component).
    </p>

    <p style="margin-top: 4ex">
      Carrot uses several open source projects -- we would like to thank
      all the contributors and supporters of free and open source software. 
    </p>
  </content>
</page>
