<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="faq">
  <heading>FAQ</heading>

  <content>
    <p class="qa">
      <div class="q">Can I use Carrot<sup>2</sup> in a commercial project?</div>
      <div class="a">
        Yes. The only requirement is that you properly acknowledge the use of
        Carrot<sup>2</sup> (on the project's website and documentation) and let
        us know about your project. Please also remember to read the <a
        content="license">license</a>.
      </div>
    </p>

    <p class="qa">
      <div class="q">I'd like to add Carrot<sup>2</sup> clustering to my existing search engine. Where do I start?</div>
      <div class="a">
        <p>
          You need to create an <a content="architecture">input component</a>
          that gets search results from your engine and feeds them to
          Carrot<sup>2</sup>. Please see the <a
          content="documentation">documentation</a>, API reference and source
          code of existing input components for useful hints. Then, you can
          reuse some bits of the Carrot<sup>2</sup> web application (located in
          the <span class="c2element">carrot2/ applications/
          carrot2-demo-webapp</span> folder of the source repository) to
          visualize the clusters.
        </p>

        <p>
          Alternatively, you can expose your search results as an <a
          href="http://opensearch.a9.com/">OpenSearch</a> feed and use
          Carrot<sup>2</sup>'s built-in OpenSearch input component. In any
          case, if you need more help, please <a content="support">let us
          know</a>.
        </p>
      </div>
    </p>

    <p class="qa">
      <div class="q">Can Carrot<sup>2</sup> crawl my website?</div>
      <div class="a">
        No. Carrot<sup>2</sup> can add clustering of search results to an
        existing search engine. You can use an Open Source project called <a
        href="http://www.nutch.org">Nutch</a> to crawl your website. Nutch has
        a Carrot<sup>2</sup>-based search clustering plugin, so you'll get all
        crawling, searching and clustering in one piece. If you need help
        with any of these, please <a content="support">contact us</a>.
      </div>
    </p>
  </content>
</page>
