<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="authors">
  <heading>Authors</heading>

  <content>
   
    <div style="width: 48%; float: left">
      <p class="author-profile">
        <a href="http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/dweiss"><img
        src="img/dawid-weiss.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px"
        class="author-photo" alt="Dawid Weiss photo" /> Dawid Weiss</a>, PhD, the
        founder of the Carrot<sup>2</sup> project, is an associate professor at
        the Laboratory of Intelligent Decision Support Systems, Institute of
        Computing Science, Poznan University of Technology, Poland.
      </p>

      <p class="author-profile">
        His research interests include text clustering, information retrieval,
        web mining, computational linguistics and software engineering. 
      </p>
    </div>

    <div style="width: 48%; float: right">
      <p style="clear: both;" class="author-profile">
        <a href="http://stanislaw.osinski.name"><img src="img/stanislaw-osinski.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px" class="author-photo" alt="Stanislaw Osinski photo" /> 
        Stanislaw Osinski</a> is the co-founder at <a
        href="http://company.carrot-search.com">Carrot Search</a>.
      </p>

      <p class="author-profile">
        His research interests
        include search results clustering, information retrieval, text mining,
        user interface design and usability. He received his MSc degrees from
        Poznan University of Technology and The University of Sheffield.
      </p>
    </div>

    Other contributors:
    <ul>
      <li>
        Urszula Krukar, (Poznan University of Technology (PUT), Poland, initial version of <c2 /> Clustering Workbench, active since 2007), 
      </li>

      <li>
      Karol Gołembniak, Irmina Masłowska (PUT, Poland, HAOG clustering component, not active), 
      </li>
     
      <li>
      Michał Wróblewski (PUT, Poland, AHC clustering components, not active),
      </li>
      
      <li>
      Paweł Kowalik (PUT, Poland, Inductive search engine wrapper, not active),
      </li>

      <li>
      Steven Schockaert (University of Gent, Belgium, Fuzzy Ants clustering component, not active),
      </li>

      <li>
      Lang Ngo Chi (Warsaw University, Poland, Fuzzy Rough set clustering component, not active),
      </li>

      <li>
      <a href="http://www.digitalpebble.com/">Julien
      Nioche</a> (DigitalPebble, UK, OpenSearch input component),
      </li>

      <li>
      Reinhard Schwab (improvements to the Lingo clustering algorithm),
      </li>

      <li>
      Sairaj Sunil (enhancements to the Lucene input component).
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p style="margin-top: 4ex">
      Carrot uses several open source projects -- we would like to thank
      all the contributors and supporters of free and open source software. 
    </p>
  </content>
</page>
