<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="faq">
  <heading>FAQ</heading>

  <content>
    <faqs>
    <faq id="testing">
      <question>How can I try <c2 /> with my own data?</question>
      <answer>
        Please see <man /> for a number of 
        <manual-link section="section.getting-started">typical <c2 /> testing scenarios</manual-link>.
      </answer>
    </faq>
    
    <faq id="integration">
      <question>How can I integrate <c2 /> with my software?</question>
      <answer>
        Please see <man /> for information about 
        <manual-link section="section.integration">integrating <c2 /> with Java and non-Java software</manual-link>.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="crawling">
      <question>Can <c2 /> crawl my website?</question>
      <answer>
        No. <c2 /> can add clustering of search results to an
        existing search engine. You can use an Open Source project called <a
        href="http://www.nutch.org">Nutch</a> to crawl your website. Nutch has
        a <c2 />-based search clustering plugin, so you'll get all
        crawling, searching and clustering in one piece. If you need help
        with any of these, please <a content="contact">contact us</a>.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="other-uses">
      <question>Can I use <c2 /> to cluster something else than search results?</question>
      <answer>
        Absolutely. <c2 /> came about as a framework for building search results clustering
        engines but its algorithms should successfully cluster up to about a thousand
        text documents, a few paragraphs each. 
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="classification">
      <question>Can I force <c2 /> to cluster my documents to some predefined clusters / labels?</question>
      <answer>
        No. Assigning documents to a set of predefined categories is a problem called
        text classification / categorization and <c2 /> was not designed to solve it.
        For text classification components you may want to see the 
        <a href="http://alias-i.com/lingpipe/">LingPipe project</a>.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="scalability">
      <question>How does <c2 /> clustering scale with respect to the number and length of documents?</question>
      <answer>
        The most important characteristic of <c2 /> algorithms to keep in mind
        is that they perform in-memory clustering. For this reason, as a rule of thumb, <c2 /> should
        successfully deal with up to a thousand of documents, a few paragraphs each.
        For algorithms designed to process millions of documents, you may want to check 
        out the <a href="http://lucene.apache.org/mahout/">Mahout project</a>.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="clustering-without-query">
      <question>Can I perform clustering without specifying the query?</question>
      <answer>
        Yes. While the query is usually very helpful to get rid of the obvious
        meanings related to the documents in the search results set, it is not
        obligatory -- the clustering algorithms will cope without the query.
      </answer>
    </faq>
   
    <faq id="compiling">
      <question>How do I compile <c2 /> source code?</question>
      <answer>
        Please see <man /> for more information on 
        <manual-link section="section.advanced-topics.building-from-source-code">compiling <c2 /> source code</manual-link>.
      </answer>
    </faq>
    
    <faq id="maven">
      <question>How do I get started if I use Maven2?</question>
      <answer>
        Please see <man /> for information about <manual-link section="section.integration.adding-to-maven-project">adding 
        a <c2 /> dependency to an existing Maven2 project</manual-link> or <manual-link section="section.integration.setting-up-maven-project">setting up
        a <c2 /> Maven2 project from scratch</manual-link>.
      </answer>
    </faq>    
    
    <faq id="corrupted-characters">
      <question>Why do I see "?" characters instead of my Chinese/ Polish/ other Unicode characters?</question>
      <answer>
        Please see <man /> for 
        <manual-link section="section.troubleshooting.webapp.uri-encoding">troubleshooting URI encoding problems</manual-link>.
      </answer>
    </faq>    

    <faq id="commercial">
      <question>Can I use <c2 /> in a commercial project?</question>
      <answer>
        Yes. The only requirement is that you include the <a
        content="license">license</a> text in your binary distribution.
        It'd be great if you let us know about your project and/or acknowledged
        the use of Carrot2 on your project's website or documentation. It's
        optional, but keeps us motivated :-)
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="acknowledging">
      <question>How can I acknowledge the use of <c2 /> on my site?</question>
      <answer>
        Please put a statement equivalent to "This product includes software
        developed by the Carrot2 Project" on your site and link it to
        <c2 />'s website (<a
        href="http://www.carrot2.org">http://www.carrot2.org</a>). Additionally,
        you can use some of our <a content="acknowledging">powered-by logos</a>
        if you like.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    <faq id="circles">
      <question>Can I get the source code of the <a href="http://search.carrot2.org/stable/search?source=web&amp;view=visu&amp;query=data+mining&amp;results=100&amp;algorithm=url" target="_blank">clusters visualization</a>?</question>
      <answer>
        Source code of the visualization is not publicly available. For
        a fully brandable version, please see the <a href="http://carrotsearch.com/circles">Circles 
        interative clusters visualization</a> from Carrot Search.
      </answer>
    </faq>
    
    <faq id="webapp">
      <question>How do I set up/ modify/ get the output similar to what I see on <a href="http://search.carrot2.org">http://search.carrot2.org</a></question>
      <answer>
        The focus of the Carrot2 project is on <i>clustering algorithms</i>. We provide several higher-level applications such as the
        web application hosted at <a href="http://search.carrot2.org">http://search.carrot2.org</a>, an RCP-based Workbench desktop
        application for tuning purposes and a simple REST-service server DCS which is a command-line application. All these applications are
        to some point extensible but are not the core concern of developers, so before you ask a question on the mailing
        list it's best to checkout the project, see how these applications work first (in particular
        look at the build files that collect data for these applications) and try to modify them on your own. For generic questions such as 
        "how can I tune/ modify the web application" we have a generic answer: "by modifying the source code". Ask specific questions and you'll get
        specific answers.
      </answer>
    </faq>
    
    <faq id="bing">
      <question>Why is Bing Search not working on <a href="http://search.carrot2.org">http://search.carrot2.org</a>?</question>
      <answer>
        Microsoft provides a search API for Bing with a free monthly limit of 5000 requests. Once this
        free limit is used up, Bing-powered tabs on Carrot2 will cease working. If you'd like to use
        Bing then issue an API key for yourself, download Carrot2 applications and run them locally
        with your key.
      </answer>
    </faq>

    </faqs>
  </content>
</page>
