<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="release-3.5.2">
  <heading>Release 3.5.2</heading>

  <content>
    <para>
      <release-info version="3.5.2" />
      The 3.5.2 release of <c2 /> adds Ajax support to the Document Clustering Server, 
      updates the supported search engines and adds a number of minor improvements. 
    </para>

    <table class="release-notes">
      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Ajax support in Document Clustering Server
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
            As of the 3.5.2 release, the Document Clustering Server supports the <tt>GET</tt> 
            and <tt>POST/x-www-form-urlencoded</tt> request methods, you can now call
            the DCS directly from your Ajax applications. The Quick Start screen will help you 
            to generate example DCS requests in all supported methods.
          </p>
          <img class="pic rn" src="img/release-3.5.2/dcs-ajax.png" alt="Ajax support in Document Clustering Server" style="margin-top: 0" />
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Support for Yahoo BOSS removed
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
            Release 3.5.2 removes support for Yahoo! BOSS API, as it is no longer available free of charge.
            The Bing document source has been improved to expose search options similar
            to those offered by BOSS, including news/image search and domain restrictions.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Thai support (experimental)
        </td>

        <td>
          Release 3.5.2 adds experimental support for clustering Thai content, based on Lucene's 
          <tt>ThaiWordFilter</tt>.
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Support for native matrix computations removed
        </td>

        <td>
          Release 3.5.2 removes support for native matrix computations. For further releases,
          we will consider switching to Apache Mahout Math matrix libraries and adding native 
          computation support to these libraries.
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Improvements in Document Clustering Workbench
        </td>

        <td>
          Release 3.5.2 makes a number of improvements in the Document Clustering workbench:
          
          <ul>
            <li>
              Consistent key binding for reclustering the content of the active tab: 
              &lt;Ctrl&gt;+R on Windows/Linux and &#x2318;+R on Mac OS.
            </li>
            <li>
              Expanded/collapsed branches in the cluster tree are now preserved between reclusterings.
            </li>
            <li>
              Separate buttons for collapsing and expanding all clusters in the cluster tree.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          HPPC update
        </td>

        <td>
          <a href="http://labs.carrotsearch.com/hppc.html">High Performance Primitive Collections</a> 
          has been updated to version 0.4.1.
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table>

    <hr />

    <p>
      For a complete list of improvements and bug fixes, see <a
      href="http://issues.carrot2.org/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?reset=true&amp;jqlQuery=project+%3D+CARROT+AND+fixVersion+%3D+%223.5.2%22+ORDER+BY+priority+DESC">JIRA
      issues fixed</a> in version 3.5.2. For more new features, please see <a
      content="release-3.5.0-notes">release 3.5.0</a> and <a
      content="release-3.4.0-notes">release 3.4.0 notes</a>. 
    </p>
  </content>
</page>

