<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xsl/page.xsl" type="text/xsl" ?>

<page section="release-3.13.0">
  <heading>Release 3.13.0</heading>

  <content>
    <para>
      <release-info version="3.13.0" />
      The 3.13.0 release fixes incompatibility problems with newer servlet APIs,
      removes Google document source (API terminated) and hides Bing document source
      from public demos (free API limited to a cap of query counts that we cannot 
      provide). Other minor issues have been resolved.
    </para>

    <table class="release-notes">
      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Servlet API incompatibility
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
             A servlet API incompatibility has been fixed that caused visualizations
             to load for a very long time. Built-in response compression has been removed
             as well, if you wish to have compressed HTTP responses, configure it at
             your servlet container level.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>

      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Google removed
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
             Google has terminated the search API and has been removed from the code.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>           
      
      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          Workbench updates
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
             The source view in the Workbench wasn't saving all attributes (including the query). All
             attributes are now saved, so if you export attributes make sure the query isn't included
             or it'll be treated as the default.
          </p>
          <p>
             Another issue affected rendering of results list on high-DPI screens, this is now fixed.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>           
      
      <tr>
        <td class="head">
          ISO language codes
        </td>

        <td>
          <p>
             ISO language codes for Greek, Czech, Estonian and Irish were wrong, they are now correct.
          </p>
        </td>
      </tr>                 
    </table>

    <hr />

    <p>
      For a complete list of improvements and bug fixes, see <a href="http://goo.gl/g9YFmx">JIRA</a> 
    </p>
  </content>
</page>

